Guide to the Rosetta Reitz Papers, 1929-2008
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Writings Series, 1959-2006, (6 boxes)
  - Other Unpublished Music Writings, 1977-1998 and undated
    - Related Research Notes, (3 folders) (Box 14)
      Clippings, notes, and other material related to Reitz's various music writings.
    - Related Research Notes, continued, (7 folders) (Box 15)
  - Published Music Writings, 1973-1992
    Arranged chronologically.
    - Riffs, a recurring column in The Village Voice (1973-1974). (Box 15)
    - Various Short Pieces (1980). (Box 15)
      Brief published articles on topics including Sippie Wallace, Bessie Smith, and other female jazz and blues musicians.
    - The Blues of Sippie Wallace and B.B. King, Montreux-Detroit Jazz Festival Program (August 28 - September 1, 1980), pp. 40-41, 43. (Box 15)
    - Women Blow Their Own Horns, Kool Jazz Festival Program (June 26 - July 5, 1981). (Box 15)
    - The Apollo, in Motown Returns to the Apollo, 50th Anniversary (New York: Jewell Jackson McCabe Associates, 1985), pp. 26-34, 94-99. (Box 15)
    - Sweethearts on Parade, Helicon Nine: The Journal of Women's Arts and Letters (1986). (Box 15)
    - Big Mamas, Hot Wire: The Journal of Women's Music and Culture 8/3 (September 1992), pp. 18-21. (Box 15)
    - Bessie Smith: Empress of the Blues, in Notable Black American Women (Detroit: Gale Research, 1992). (Box 15)
  - Feminist Writings, 1971-2002
    - Menopause: A Positive Approach (Radnor, PA: Chilton Book Company, 1977), 1977-2002; (4 folders) (Box 16)
      Correspondence, research files, order forms, advertisements, dust jackets, reviews, and related material.
    - Other Feminist Writings, 1971-1996, (6 folders) (Box 16)
      Published and unpublished writings by Reitz, including her article, The Liberation of the Yiddisha Mama (1971) and her grassroots advocacy for a US postage stamp honoring Bessie Smith (1979-1996).
  - Food Writings, 1959-1971
    Research notes, correspondence, article submissions, and other material related to Reitz's writings on food, recipes, and restaurants.
    - Food writings, (7 folders) (Box 16)
- Photographs Series, (3 boxes)
  Individual photographs, primarily 8x10 publicity shots, of jazz and blues musicians. Also contains images related to Reitz's presentations or intended for use in Reitz's publications.
  - Individual Photos
    8x10 publicity shots of individual musicians.
    - Ammons, Gene (Box 17)
    - Anderson, Ivie (Box 17)
    - Anderson, Marian (Box 17)
    - Armstrong, Lil (Box 17)
    - Armstrong, Louis (Box 17)
    - Baker, Josephine (Box 17)
    - Barnes, Mae (Box 17)
    - Bartz, Gary (Box 17)
    - Bennett, Tony (Box 17)
    - Bryant, Willie (Box 17)
    - Booze, Wee Bae (Box 17)
    - Bradley, Ruth (Box 17)
    - Bricktop (Box 17)
    - Brooks, Hadda (Box 17)
    - Broonzy, Big Bill (Box 17)
    - Brown, Jewel (Box 17)
    - Brown, Lilian (Box 17)
    - Brown, Ruth (Box 17)
    - Buggs, Marie (Box 17)
    - Butterbeans and Susie (Box 17)
    - Carlisle, Una Mae (Box 17)
    - Carpenter, Thelma (Box 17)
    - Carter, Betty (Box 17)
    - Carter, Nell (Box 17)
    - Coltrane, John (Box 17)
    - Crooker, Dorothy (Box 17)
    - Donegan, Dorothy (Box 17)
    - Ellington, Duke (Box 17)
    - Fitzgerald, Ella (Box 17)
    - Franklin, Aretha (Box 17)
    - Frazee Sisters (Box 17)
    - Freeman, L Sharon (Box 17)
    - Gordon, Dexter (Box 17)
    - Green, Lil (Box 17)
    - Greenfield, Mimi (Box 17)
    - Hall, Adelaide (Box 17)
    - Hall, Audrey (Box 17)
    - Hawkins, Coleman (Box 17)
    - Heywood, Eddie (Box 17)
    - Hill, Bertha (Box 17)
    - Hines, Earl Fatha (Box 17)
    - Holiday, Billie (Box 17)
    - Hopkins, Linda (Box 17)
    - Horne, Lena (Box 17)
    - Humes, Helen (Box 17)
    - Humphrey, Bobbi (Box 17)
    - Hunter, Alberta (Box 17)
    - Hutton, Ina Ray (Box 17)
    - International Sweethearts of Rhythm (Box 17)
    - James, Etta (Box 17)
    - Johnson, Ella (Box 17)
    - Johnson, James P. (Box 17)
    - Johnson, Lonnie (Box 17)
    - Jones, Albinia (Box 17)
    - Laine, Cleo (Box 17)
    - Lee, Peggy (Box 17)
    - Lincoln, Abbey (Box 17)
    - Marcelle, Miss (Box 17)
    - Maria, Diamond Teeth (Box 17)
    - Martin, Sarah (Box 17)
    - McCoy, Viola (Box 17)
    - McDaniel, Hattie (Box 17)
    - McKinney, Nina Mae (Box 17)
    - McPartland, Marian (Box 17)
    - McRae, Carmen (Box 17)
    - Mercer, Mabel (Box 17)
    - Merritt, Theresa (Box 17)
    - Miles, Lizzie (Box 17)
    - Minnie, Memphis (Box 17)
    - Murphy, Rose (Box 17)
    - Nelson, Novella (Box 17)
    - Parker, Charlie (Box 17)
    - Parker, Gloria (Box 17)
    - Raelets, The (Box 17)
    - Rainey, Ma (Box 17)
    - Reitz, Rosetta (Box 17)
    - Revolutionary Ensemble (Box 17)
    - Rosie the Riveter (Box 17)
    - Scott, Hazel (Box 17)
    - Shipp, Ginger Smock (Box 18)
    - Singer, Lillian (Box 18)
    - Slavin, Estelle (Box 18)
    - Smith, Bessie (Box 18)
    - Smith, Clara (Box 18)
    - Smith, Mamie (Box 18)
    - Smith, Viola (Box 18)
    - Snow, Valaida (Box 18)
    - Spivey, Victoria (Box 18)
    - Sticht, Betty (Box 18)
    - Sullivan, Maxine (Box 18)
    - Sylvester, Hannah (Box 18)
    - Taylor, Eva (Box 18)
    - Taylor, Koko (Box 18)
    - Thomas, Hociel (Box 18)
    - Thomas, Irma (Box 18)
    - Thornton, Big Mama (Box 18)
    - Tucker, Sophie (Box 18)
    - Tyner, McCoy (Box 18)
    - Vaughan, Sarah (Box 18)
    - Walker, Ada Overton (Box 18)
    - Walker, Madame C.J. (Box 18)
    - Wallace, Sippie (Box 18)
    - Walsh, Kay (Box 18)
    - Washington, Dinah (Box 18)
    - Waters, Ethel (Box 18)
    - Wells, Darlene (Box 18)
    - West, Mae (Box 18)
    - Williams, Mary Lou (Box 18)
    - Wilson, Edith (Box 18)
    - Wilson, Teddy (Box 18)
    - Young, Lester (Box 18)
    - Unidentified Subjects (Box 18)
  - Themed Photos
    - Photos for inclusion in book manuscript Women's Blues and Jazz: Their Magic 1920 to 1950s (Box 18)
    - Photos from Blues is a Woman, 1980-1981 (Box 18)
    - Photos for Jailhouse Blues Album (#1316) (Box 18)
    - Photographic proofs by Duncan Schiedt (Box 18)
  - Negatives and Slides
    Contains negatives and/or slides of some of the images from Box 17 and Box 18. A significant number relate to the various presentations of Blues Is a Woman.
    - Negatives and Slides (Box 19)
- Posters Series, (1 box)
  Posters related to Reitz's presentations and research, including various promotional posters for Shouters and Wailers presentations along with those related to individual female jazz and blues musicians. (3 folders)
  - Posters (Box 20)
- Audio and Moving Image Series, 1929-2002, (15 boxes)
  Contains all of the commercial audio recordings released by Rosetta Records in cassette, LP, and/or CD format. Also contains noncommercial recordings of the Blues is a Woman presentations and other events featuring Reitz. The moving image materials primarily comprise VHS and 16 mm film of musical performances that originally aired on television, compiled by Reitz as a part of her ongoing research into female jazz and blues musicians. Arranged by format.
  - Audio Cassettes, 1980-1994 and undated
    - Commercial Recordings
      Arranged by official Rosetta Records catalog numbers. CD use copies are available in Box 58.
      - RC 1300: Mean Mothers. Independent Women’s Blues, Volume 1. Women’s Heritage Series (Rosetta Records and Tapes, 1980). (Box 21)
      - RC 1303: Piano Singer’s Blues: 16 Historic Foremothers Accompany Themselves. Women’s Heritage Series (Rosetta Records and Tapes, 1982). (Box 21)
      - RC 1306: Big Mamas. Independent Women’s Blues, Volume 2. Women’s Heritage Series (Rosetta Records and Tapes, 1985). (Box 21)
      - RC 1308: Super Sisters. Independent Women’s Blues, Volume 3. Women’s Heritage Series (Rosetta Records and Tapes, 1985). (Box 21)
      - RC 1310: Lil Green. Foremothers, Volume 5. Women’s Heritage Series (Rosetta Records and Tapes, 1985). (Box 21)
      - RC 1311: Sweet Petunias. Independent Women’s Blues, Volume 4. Women’s Heritage Series (Rosetta Records and Tapes, no date). (Box 21)
      - RC 1312: International Sweethearts of Rhythm. Women’s Heritage Series (Rosetta Records and Tapes, 1985). (Box 21)
      - RC 1313: Dinah Washington: Wise Woman Blues. Foremothers, Volume 4. Women’s Heritage Series (Rosetta Records and Tapes, 1985). (Box 21)
      - RC 1314: Ethel Waters: 1938-1939. Foremothers, Volume 6. (Rosetta Records and Tapes, 1986). (Box 21)
      - RC 1315: Mae West: Sixteen Sultry Songs. Foremothers, Volume 7. Women’s Heritage Series (Rosetta Records and Tapes, no date). (Box 21)
      - RC 1316: Jailhouse Blues. Women’s Heritage Series (Rosetta Records and Tapes, 1987). (Box 21)
      - RC 1317: Sister Rosetta Tharpe: Sacred and Secular. Foremothers, Volume 3. Women’s Heritage Series (Rosetta Records and Tapes, no date). (Box 21)
      - RC 1318: Dorothy Romps: A Piano Retrospective 1953-1979. Foremothers, Volume 9. Women’s Heritage Series (Rosetta Records and Tapes, 1991). (Box 21)
    - Noncommercial Recordings
      Original titles have been retained. CD use copies are available in Box 58.
      - 101: Blues is a Woman (parts 1-2). July 2, 1980. (Box 21)
      - 102: Blues is a Woman (parts 3-4). July 2, 1980. (Box 21)
      - 103: Hollywood Bowl Rehearsal with Linda Hopkins, Vi Redd, Sammy Price, Big Mama Thornton, and Carmen McRae. July 28, 1981. (Box 21)
      - 104-105: Jazz Alive! Fall Premier, The Blues is a Woman - Hollywood Bowl. July 29, 1981., (two cassettes) (Box 21)
      - 106: Interview with Rosetta Reitz. March 10, 1985. (Box 21)
      - 107: Interview with Rosetta Reitz. March 8, 1991. (Box 21)
      - 108: Sweethearts Meeting. (Box 21)
        Meeting among Rosetta Reitz, Rebecca Reitz, Greta Schiller, and Andrea Weiss regarding legal disputes over the production of the International Sweethearts of Rhythm documentary film.
      - 109: Voice of America, Bessie Centennial. April 8, 1994. (Box 21)
  - Compact Disc, 1990
    - RRCD 1300: Mean Mothers. Independent Women’s Blues, Volume 1. Women’s Heritage Series (Rosetta Records and Tapes, 1990). (Box 21)
  - Open Reel Audio Tape
    - Brown Bee Boogie by Hazel Scott. Undated. (Box 21)
  - LPs, 1980-1988 and undated
    Contains commercial releases by Rosetta Records. Arranged by official Rosetta Records catalog numbers. CD use copies are available in Box 58.
    - RR 1300: Mean Mothers. Independent Women’s Blues, Volume 1. Women’s Heritage Series (Rosetta Records and Tapes, 1980). (Box 22)
    - RR 1301: Sorry But I Can’t Take You: Women’s Railroad Blues. Women’s Heritage Series (Rosetta Records and Tapes, 1980). (Box 22)
    - RR 1302: Red, White, and Blues: Women Sing of America. Women’s Heritage Series (Rosetta Records and Tapes, no date). (Box 22)
    - RR 1303: Piano Singer’s Blues: Women Accompany Themselves. Women’s Heritage Series (Rosetta Records and Tapes, 1982). (Box 22)
    - RR 1304: Ida Cox: Wild Women Don’t Have the Blues. Foremothers, Volume 1. Women’s Heritage Series (Rosetta Records and Tapes, 1981). (Box 22)
    - RR 1305: Hot Snow: Valaida Snow Queen of the Trumpet Sings and Swings. Foremothers, Volume 2. Women’s Heritage Series (Rosetta Records and Tapes, 1982). (Box 22)
    - RR 1306: Big Mamas. Independent Women’s Blues, Volume 2. Women’s Heritage Series (Rosetta Records and Tapes, 1982). (Box 22)
    - RR 1307: Georgia White Sings and Plays the Blues. Foremothers, Volume 3. Women’s Heritage Series (Rosetta Records and Tapes, 1982). [album cover only; no LP] (Box 22)
    - RR 1308: Super Sisters. Independent Women’s Blues, Volume 3. Women’s Heritage Series (Rosetta Records and Tapes, 1982). (Box 22)
    - RR 1309: Boogie Blues: Women Sing and Play Boogie Woogie. Women’s Heritage Series (Rosetta Records and Tapes, 1983). [album cover only; no LP] (Box 22)
    - RR 1310: Lil Green: Chicago 1940-1947. Foremothers, Volume 5. Women’s Heritage Series (Rosetta Records and Tapes, 1985). (Box 23)
    - RR 1311: Sweet Petunias. Independent Women’s Blues, Volume 4. Women’s Heritage Series (Rosetta Records and Tapes, no date). [album cover only; no LP] (Box 23)
    - RR 1312: International Sweethearts of Rhythm. Women’s Heritage Series (Rosetta Records and Tapes, 1984). [album cover only; no LP] (Box 23)
    - RR 1313: Dinah Washington: Wise Woman Blues. Foremothers, Volume 4. Women’s Heritage Series (Rosetta Records and Tapes, 1984). (Box 23)
    - RR 1314: Ethel Waters: 1938-1939. Foremothers, Volume 6. Women’s Heritage Series (Rosetta Records and Tapes, 1986). (Box 23)
    - RR 1315: Mae West: Sixteen Sultry Songs. Foremothers, Volume 7. Women’s Heritage Series (Rosetta Records and Tapes, 1987). (Box 23)
    - RR 1316: Jailhouse Blues. Women’s Heritage Series (Rosetta Records and Tapes, 1987). (Box 23)
    - RR 1317: Sincerely, Sister Rosetta Tharpe: Sacred and Secular. Foremothers, Volume 8. Women’s Heritage Series (Rosetta Records and Tapes, 1988). (Box 23)
  - CD and DVD Use Copies
    Contains CD use copies for audio materials in boxes 21-23 and DVD use copies of scanned images of all LP covers and liner notes. Identified by official Rosetta Records catalog numbers or by assigned number, for noncommercial material.
    - CD Use Copies of Commercial Recordings
      Identified by official Rosetta Records catalog numbers.
      - Digital copy of Mean Mothers. Independent Women’s Blues, Volume 1. Women’s Heritage Series (Rosetta Records and Tapes, 1980). (Box 58, Cd 1300)
      - Digital copy of Sorry But I Can’t Take You: Women’s Railroad Blues. Women’s Heritage Series (Rosetta Records and Tapes, 1980). (Box 58, Cd 1301)
      - Digital copy of Red, White, and Blues: Women Sing of America. Women’s Heritage Series (Rosetta Records and Tapes, no date) (Box 58, Cd 1302)
      - Digital copy of Piano Singer’s Blues: Women Accompany Themselves. Women’s Heritage Series (Rosetta Records and Tapes, 1982). (Box 58, Cd 1303)
      - Digital copy of Ida Cox: Wild Women Don’t Have the Blues. Foremothers, Volume 1. Women’s Heritage Series (Rosetta Records and Tapes, 1981). (Box 58, Cd 1304)
      - Digital copy of Hot Snow: Valaida Snow Queen of the Trumpet Sings and Swings. Foremothers, Volume 2. Women’s Heritage Series (Rosetta Records and Tapes, 1982). (Box 58, Cd 1305)
      - Digital copy of Big Mamas. Independent Women’s Blues, Volume 2. Women’s Heritage Series (Rosetta Records and Tapes, 1982). (Box 58, Cd 1306)
      - Digital copy of Georgia White Sings and Plays the Blues. Foremothers, Volume 3. Women’s Heritage Series (Rosetta Records and Tapes, 1982). (Box 58, Cd 1307)
      - Digital copy of Super Sisters. Independent Women’s Blues, Volume 3. Women’s Heritage Series (Rosetta Records and Tapes, 1982). (Box 58, Cd 1308)
      - Digital copy of Boogie Blues: Women Sing and Play Boogie Woogie. Women’s Heritage Series (Rosetta Records and Tapes, 1983). (Box 58, Cd 1309)
      - Digital copy of Lil Green: Chicago 1940-1947. Foremothers, Volume 5. Women’s Heritage Series (Rosetta Records and Tapes, 1985). (Box 58, Cd 1310)
      - Digital copy of Sweet Petunias. Independent Women’s Blues, Volume 4. Women’s Heritage Series (Rosetta Records and Tapes, no date). (Box 58, Cd 1311)
      - Digital copy of International Sweethearts of Rhythm. Women’s Heritage Series (Rosetta Records and Tapes, 1984). (Box 58, Cd 1312)
      - Digital copy of Dinah Washington: Wise Woman Blues. Foremothers, Volume 4. Women’s Heritage Series (Rosetta Records and Tapes, 1984). (Box 58, Cd 1313)
      - Digital copy of Ethel Waters: 1938-1939. Foremothers, Volume 6. Women’s Heritage Series (Rosetta Records and Tapes, 1986). (Box 58, Cd 1314)
      - Digital copy of Mae West: Sixteen Sultry Songs. Foremothers, Volume 7. Women’s Heritage Series (Rosetta Records and Tapes, 1987). (Box 58, Cd 1315)
      - Digital copy of Jailhouse Blues. Women’s Heritage Series (Rosetta Records and Tapes, 1987). (Box 58, Cd 1316)
      - Digital copy of Sincerely, Sister Rosetta Tharpe: Sacred and Secular. Foremothers, Volume 8. Women’s Heritage Series (Rosetta Records and Tapes, 1988). (Box 58, Cd 1317)
      - Digital copy of Dorothy Romps: A Piano Retrospective 1953-1979. Foremothers, Volume 9. Women’s Heritage Series (Rosetta Records and Tapes, 1991). (Box 58, Cd 1318)
    - CD Use Copies of Noncommercial Recordings
      Original titles have been retained.
      - Blues is a Woman, Part 1, 43 mins, July 2, 1980, JAD-2009-0003-101A (Box 58, Cd 1)
      - Blues is a Woman, Part 2, 15 mins, July 2, 1980, JAD-2009-0003-101B (Box 58)
      - Blues is a Woman, Part 3, 25 mins, July 2, 1980, JAD-2009-0003-102A (Box 58, Cd 2)
      - Blues is a Woman, Part 4, 27 mins, July 2, 1980, JAD-2009-0003-102B (Box 58)
      - Hollywood Bowl Rehearsal, Part 1, July 28, 1981, JAD-2009-0003-103A (Box 58, Cd 3)
      - Hollywood Bowl Rehearsal, Part 2, July 28, 1981, JAD-2009-0003-103B (Box 58)
      - Jazz Alive! - Blues is a Woman, Part 1, July 29, 1981., JAD-2009-0003-104A (Box 58, Cd 4)
      - Jazz Alive! - Blues is a Woman, Part 2, July 29, 1981, JAD-2009-0003-104B (Box 58, Cd 5)
      - Jazz Alive! - Blues is a Woman, Part 3, July 29, 1981, JAD-2009-0003-105A (Box 58, Cd 6)
      - Jazz Alive! - Blues is a Woman, Part 4, July 29, 1981, JAD-2009-0003-105B (Box 58)
      - Interview with Rosetta Reitz, Part 1, March 10, 1985, JAD-2009-0003-106A (Box 58, Cd 7)
      - Interview with Rosetta Reitz, Part 2, March 10, 1985, JAD-2009-0003-106B (Box 58)
      - Interview with Rosetta Reitz, Part 1, March 8, 1991, JAD-2009-0003-107A (Box 58, Cd 8)
      - Interview with Rosetta Reitz, Part 2, March 8, 1991, JAD-2009-0003-107B (Box 58)
      - Sweethearts Meeting, Part 1, JAD-2009-0003-108A (Box 58, Cd 9)
      - Sweethearts Meeting, Part 2, JAD-2009-0003-108B (Box 58)
      - Voice of America, Bessie Centennial, April 8, 1994, JAD-2009-0003-109A (Box 58)
    - DVD Use Copies of LP covers and liner notes
      LP covers were scanned for RR1300-RR1317, while cassette covers were scanned for RR1318.
      - Digital copies of LP covers and liner notes, Content (Box 58, Dvd 1)
  - VHS, 1984-2002 and undated
    Consists primarily of recordings of musical performances from various television shows, compiled by Reitz as a part of her ongoing research into female jazz musicians. Interspersed throughout are a few commercially released videos, including in Box 24 Jazz Women on Video, produced by Rosetta Records in 1990, and two videos on the Piney Woods School--the home institution for the International Sweethearts of Rhythm.
    - Cotton Club Remembered: Oscar Peterson – Ella at Wolftrap (Box 24)
    - Saying it with Jazz: Carmen, Etta Songs, etc (Box 24)
    - Vaudeville (Box 24)
    - Kit McClure Band: Live in Japan 1992 (Box 24)
    - Josephine Baker Documentary (Box 24)
    - Bessie Smith Doc, Women Film Pioneers, Carmen McRay (Box 24)
    - Stormy Weather (Box 24)
    - Mary Lou Williams: Music on My Mind and Aretha Franklin: Queen of Soul (Box 24)
    - Introduction to the Piney Woods Country Life School (Box 24)
    - Say Amen Somebody (Box 24)
    - That’s Dancing/Piney Woods Moms Mabley (Box 24)
    - Radical Harmonies: Woodstock Meets Women’s Liberation (prod. Woman Vision, 2002). (Box 24)
    - Jazz Women on Video, prod. Rosetta Records, 1990 (RRV 1320) [two copies, with a third, earlier production copy] (Box 24)
    - Cairo with Ethel Waters, 1942 (Box 25)
    - Rufus Jones, Louis and Maxine, Ethel with Ed Murrow, Cairo (Box 25)
    - Bessie Smith, Nina Mae McKinney, Billie Holiday (Box 25)
    - Women in Jazz Shows #37-39 (Box 25)
    - Piano Blues, Scorcese (Box 25)
    - [unlabeled] (Box 25)
    - JVC Jazz Festival 1988 (Box 25)
    - Brown Sugar, Parts 1 and 2 (Box 25)
    - Rhapsody in Blue, Life of Gershwin, Jolson Singing Fool (Box 25)
    - International Sweethearts of Rhythm (Box 25)
    - Various Blues (Box 25)
    - Ella bio, 2 hours (Box 25)
    - Vaudeville (Box 25)
    - Cabin in the Sky (Box 25)
    - Last of the Blue Devils (Box 25)
    - The Josephine Baker Story (Box 26)
    - Paulette Goddard, Fred Astaire film (Box 26)
    - Great Singing Tradition (Box 26)
    - The Divine One Dance (Box 26)
    - The Roaring 20s, part 1 (Box 26)
    - The Roaring 20s, part 2 (Box 26)
    - Day at the Races: Ivie Anderson (Box 26)
    - Sarah Bio, Billie Bio, Fats Bio (Box 26)
    - Betty Carter, 1986; Ella, Essence, 1986 (Box 26)
    - Brown Sugar #4 (Box 26)
    - The Sound of Jazz (Box 26)
    - Josephine Baker (Box 26)
    - Many Faces of Lady Day, Aretha (Box 26)
    - Dorothy (Box 26)
    - Sarah Memorial (Box 26)
    - Etta James, Sippie Wallace, Ella, Linda Hopkins, Leatta Galloway, Vi Redd (Box 27)
    - Minnie the Moocher, Wynton Marsalis, Greta Schiller Stonewall Interview (Box 27)
    - Jazz on a Summer’s Day (Box 27)
    - Lena with Benny Carter, 1943 (Box 27)
    - All Girl Bands, The Big Bands (Box 27)
    - Ragtime, Madame CJ Walker (Box 27)
    - Alberta Hunter (Box 27)
    - Ethel Waters, Sippie Wallace, Jazz Dance, After Hours, Boswell Sisters (Box 27)
    - Blues, Scorcese, Volume 1 (Box 27)
    - Ella sings two songs on Ed Sullivan Show (Box 27)
    - Nell Carter, Danny Barker (Box 27)
    - Women Big Bands (Box 27)
    - Carmen McRae, Live in Tokyo, 1986 (Box 27)
    - The Big Bands, prod. Wally Heider, Swingtime Video, Inc, 1984 (Box 28)
    - Duke Ellington and His Orchestra, Jazz Classics, 1986 (JCVC 101) (Box 28)
    - Louis Armstrong and His Orchestra, Jazz Classics, 1986 (JCVC 102) (Box 28)
    - Louis Jordan and Friends, Jazz Classics, 1986 (JCVC 105) (Box 28)
    - Nat King Cole Plus Mills Brothers and Delta Rhythm Boys, Jazz Classics, 1986 (JCVC 106) (Box 28)
    - Bessie Smith and Friends, Jazz Classics, 1986 (JCVC 108) (Box 28)
    - Harlem Harmonies, Jazz Classics, 1986 (JCVC 110) (Box 28)
    - Dizzy Gillespie, Jazz Classics, 1986 (JCVC 115) (Box 28)
    - Count Basie and Friends, Jazz Classics, 1986 (JCVC 109) (Box 28)
  - Umatic Tapes, 1980-1981 and undated
    Dubs of three interviews/performances from television shows.
    - Blues is a Woman NBC, 1980; and Wild Women Don’t Have the Blues WNBC-TV, 1981 (two copies) (Box 29)
    - Wild Women Don’t Have the Blues WNBC-TV, 1981 (Box 29)
    - Blues is a Woman NBC, 1980 (Box 29)
    - Sippie Wallace: interview and performance with her own band no date (Box 29)
    - Sippie Wallace Segment, not for air WTVS, no date (Box 29)
  - 16mm Film, 1929-1977 and undated
    - F101: Mae Barnes and Three Whippets from Chicago and All that Jazz (3 minutes) (Box 30)
    - F102: Ethel Waters, Am I Blue? (Box 30)
    - F103: Sophisticated Gals; What Can the Matter Be – Nobody Makes a Pass at Me; I’m a Big Girl Now; Memphis Blues (Box 30)
    - F104: Nicholas Young Brothers and Eunice Wilson (Box 30)
    - F105: Bessie Smith, St. Louis Blues with violence and racism removed (9 minutes) (Box 30)
    - F106: Jammin the Blues, 2nd copy from negative; the good one; no static (Box 30)
    - F107: Jammin the Blues, scratchy sound (10 minutes) (Box 30)
    - F108: Nellie Lutcher, He’s a Real Gone Guy 1955 (3 minutes) (Box 30)
    - F109: Lil Armstrong with Mae Barnes, Lil’s Boogie from Chicago and All that Jazz (Box 30)
    - F110: International Sweethearts of Rhythm, That Man of Mine (3 minutes) (Box 30)
    - F111: Tchaikovskiana; Dave Schooler and His 21 Swinghearts [poor condition; needs further attention] (Box 30)
    - F112: Josephine Baker snippets (4 minutes) (Box 30)
    - F113: Billie Holiday, Do You Know What it Means To Miss New Orleans? 1947 (4 ½ minutes) (Box 30)
    - F114: Cuban Rhythms (Luba Melina in Cuban Pete; Jeri Sullivan in Rum and Coca Cola; The Lady in Red Go To See the Nutch Girl from Cuba) (Box 30)
    - F115: Ina Ray Hutton (12 minutes) (Bugle Call Rag; Stardust; Organ Grinders Swing; Rita Rio, Sticks and Stones) (Box 30)
    - F116: Martha Davis, Bippity, Bippitty Bop and Just Goodbye (Box 30)